#### Contact

2813 N Tee Time Ct Wichita, KS 67205 316-516-1239 (Mobile) bjwerth@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/belindawerth-95722322 (LinkedIn)

#### Top Skills

Typing
Microsoft Word
PowerPoint

Languages

English

Certifications

**CCRN** 

**TNCC Instructor** 

**PALS** 

RN

**ACLS** 

# **Belinda Werth**

Advanced Practice Nurse at Clifton Family Medicine Wichita, Kansas

### Summary

Experienced Advanced Practice Nurse with a demonstrated history of working in a family practice clinic managing complex chronic illness and acute illnesses. Strong healthcare services professional with a Doctorate of Nursing focused in Family Nurse Practitioner from Wichita State University.

## Experience

Clifton Family Medicine Advanced Practice Nurse March 2018 - Present (2 years 5 months) Wichita, Kansas Area

- # Developing treatment plans for acute and chronic diseases
- # Educating and guiding patients on disease prevention and healthy lifestyle habits
- # Understanding the changes in health promotion throughout the aging process
- # Conducting exams
- # Performing diagnostic tests and screening evaluations
- # Managing overall patient care regarding lifestyle and development issues
- # Emphasizing preventative care and disease management
- # Prescribing medications

Wesley Medical Center
Trauma Control Nurse
March 2011 - January 2018 (6 years 11 months)

- Wichita, Kansas Area
- # Responsible for the flow of the trauma room during the resuscitation of trauma patients from the time they are admitted to definitive care. Trauma nurses are responsible for maintaining order and ensuring safe, quality care of all trauma patients (adults and pediatrics).
- # Responsible for trauma triage decision making for patients who enter the facility by private vehicle or those who need further assessment upon arrival with EMS. Trauma nurses evaluate and determine level of treatment.

# Trauma nurses serve as a resource to all departments in the hospital.

Responsible for massive blood transfusions throughout the facility as a resource or expert at running the protocol for trauma department.

# Development of presentations for trauma critique meetings once a month.

Presentations serve as a communication tool between EMS and trauma department to help resolve issues and offer education.

# TNCC Instructor

Midwest Transplant Network
Organ Procurement Transplant Coordinator
2008 - 2010 (2 years)

Served a dual role at Midwest Transplant Network as Organ Procurement Coordinator and Hospital Services Coordinator. As OPC, managed the care of organ donors and coordinated the arrival of transplant teams for procurement of organs for transplant. Managed an on call schedule of 10 days per month. As HSC, maintained an assignment of hospitals to work with them in a partnership to ensure the referral of all potential organ and tissue donors. Provided education on the organ and tissue process to appropriate departments, developed strategic plans based on collection of data.

Via Christi Health System RN 2002 - 2008 (6 years)

Worked as an RN in a busy blended ICU. Managed care of surgical, trauma, heart/pancreas/kidney transplant, VAD, cardiothoracic and medical patients. Served as Relief Charge from 2004-2008. Responded to Level I and Level II traumas to assist in their admission and stabilization prior to transport to a destination. Served on the education committee, collected and maintained the unit statistics and headed a committee to increase the morale of the employees.

## Education

Wichita State University

Doctorate of Nursing, Family Nurse Practitioner · (2013 - 2017)

Wichita State University BSN, Nursing (1999 - 2002)